http://www.nationmaster.com/terms

TERMS & CONDITIONS
By using this site, you agree to the following terms and conditions:
NationMaster holds copyright on all aspects of this site (including but not limited to content and layout), except where copyrights are held by our sources.
You may not use any robot, spider or any automated or manual device to monitor or copy any aspect of this site (including content) without the NATIONMASTER
prior permission, unless your purpose is to index the content for a traditional search engine (eg. Google, Bink, etc). You may not replicate, modify,
reproduce, publish, distribute, display or transmit any portion of this web site, except as permitted in this document.
You are permitted to quote no more than 20 individual figures (eg. US GDP per capita, Andorran life expectancy, etc) or lines of text from this site,
provided you provide a link back to a valid page at NATIONMASTER. You may not copy graphs, maps, scatterplots, etc.
If you would like permission to quote the data in another way, or to make an enquiry about licensing, please contact us.
You are free to link to any page on the site, without needing to seek permission.
DISCLAIMER
Totals, averages and rankings
The data this site comes from numerous sources. NationMaster has added additional features where totals, averages and nation rankings are calculated. These can be unreliable,
as each statistic may have been collected using differing methodologies and at different times. Further, some countries will not have data for a statistic. This does not
mean that they have none of the prescribed figure (eg. no airports, no people living with HIV, etc), or even that no measurement has been made. Thus, these should only be
construed as a rough guide.
The data may be unreliable in other ways not mentioned here.
DISCLAIMER
THIS WEB SITE AND THE CONTENT ARE PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS, AS AVAILABLE" BASIS. PROVIDER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR
A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT. THE PROVIDER DISCLAIMS ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY LOSS, INJURY, CLAIM, LIABILITY, OR DAMAGE OF ANY KIND RESULTING FROM, ARISING
OUT OF OR ANY WAY RELATED TO (A) ANY HARM TO REPUTATION OR DEFAMATION OF CHARACTER, HOWSOEVER CAUSED, IN RESPECT TO, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, ANY AND ALL INDIVIDUALS OR GROUPS
SINGULARLY OR JOINTLY EITHER DEAD OR ALIVE (B) ANY THIRD PARTY WEB SITES OR CONTENT THEREIN DIRECTLY OR INDIRECTLY ACCESSED THROUGH LINKS IN THIS WEB SITE, INCLUDING BUT
NOT LIMITED TO ANY ERRORS IN OR OMISSIONS THEREFROM, (C) THE UNAVAILABILITY OF THIS WEB SITE, THE CONTENT, OR ANY PORTION THEREOF, (D) YOUR USE OF THIS WEB SITE OR THE CONTENT,
OR (E) YOUR USE OF ANY EQUIPMENT OR SOFTWARE IN CONNECTION WITH THIS WEB SITE OR THE CONTENT.
LIMITATION OF LIABILITY
PROVIDER SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOSS, INJURY, CLAIM, LIABILITY, OR DAMAGE OF ANY KIND RESULTING FROM YOUR USE OF THIS WEB SITE, THE CONTENT, THE INTERACTIVE AREAS OF
THIS WEB SITE OR ANY FACTS OR OPINIONS APPEARING ON OR THROUGH AN INTERACTIVE AREA. PROVIDER SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL, DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, PUNITIVE
OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OF ANY KIND WHATSOEVER (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, ATTORNEYS' FEES) IN ANY WAY DUE TO, RESULTING FROM, OR ARISING IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE
OF OR INABILITY TO USE THIS WEB SITE OR THE CONTENT. TO THE EXTENT THE FOREGOING LIMITATION OF LIABILITY IS PROHIBITED OR FAILS OF ITS ESSENTIAL PURPOSE, PROVIDER'S SOLE
OBLIGATION TO YOU FOR DAMAGES SHALL BE LIMITED TO $100.00.
This disclaimer may change in the future without notification.
PRIVACY POLICY
Effective on July 1, 2019
Our Commitment To Privacy
This privacy statement describes how NATIONMASTER collects and uses the personal information you provide on our website: nationmaster.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.
European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
As required by european law, NATIONMASTER follows the General Data Protection Regulation in order to protect your rights regarding personal information.
Should you have any question regarding your personal data, please contact our Data Protection Officer (gdpr@nationmaster.com)
Personal Information Gathering
We collect the following personal information from you:
When you browse our website
Technical Information such as your IP address, browser type and operating system, referring/exit pages, pages viewed, access dates
When you ask for an information
Contact details such as email, last & first name, phone number, company name
When you create your account
Contact details such as email, last & first name
Storage & Use of Personal Information
We store and use your personal information to:
Provide you with a user account
Send you requested information
Send you newsletters
Send you marketing communications, from NATIONMASTER or other companies in our group
Answer to your questions and concerns
Improve our platform
Comply with legal / tax obligations regarding applicable laws
Your rights
General Guidance
As per the GPDR, you have the rights to:
Have your data rectified / updated
Have your data removed from our system
Get access to the personal data we stored about you
For any other matter regarding your personal data and these rights, please contact our Data Protection Officer (see above).
Communications Opt-Out
You may also choose to stop receiving our newsletters or marketing communications by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at contact@nationmaster.com.
Information Obtained from Third Parties
If you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.
Information Sharings & Transfers
General Guidance
We do not rent or sell your personal information to third parties.
Transfers to third parties
We may transfer your personal data to other companies in our group. By doing such, we can provide you with the products / services suitable for your needs.
We also use third parties to ensure you the best service and may need to transfer parts of your information to these third parties, such as:
Google Analytics: our web analytics system. See https://privacy.google.com/businesses/compliance/ for more details
SendGrid: our emailing platform. We may transfer your email, last & first name, company industry to send you marketing communications. See https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/
Hotjar: our behaviour analysis platform. We may transfer your IP for geolocation purpose. See https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/gdpr-commitment.
Other events
We may also disclose your personal information:
as required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,
if NATIONMASTER is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,
to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.
Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies
NATIONMASTER cookies
We use cookies to ensure you the best quality of service, especially ease your navigation on our website. Cookies are used to store:
your authentication token if you're logged in
some profile information & preferences when you're not logged in, such as your country, currency, landing pages
Third parties tracking technologies
Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.
We also use third parties cookies to gather information about how you and others use our website. For example, we will know how many users access a specific page and which links they clicked on. We use this aggregated information to understand and optimize how our site is used. They do not include personal information
Managing cookies and tracking
Managing your cookies preferences
You can disable your cookies from your browser settings (see instructions below). Please note that disabling cookies might degrade your experience on our website and shall make it impossible to log in or purchase any product or service.
Chrome: https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=en
Firefox: https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences
Internet Explorer: https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies
Edge: https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy
Safari: https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US
Other browsers: please read the manufacturer documentation
Managing your tracking preferences
You can disable anonymous third parties tracking directly from your browser settings ("do not track").
Chrome: https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/114836?
Firefox: https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/how-do-i-turn-do-not-track-feature
Internet Explorer: https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17288/windows-internet-explorer-11-use-do-not-track
Edge: https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy
Safari: https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21416?locale=en_US
Other browsers: please read the manufacturer documentation
Security
When we collect personal information directly from you, we follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at contact@nationmaster.com.
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at contact@nationmaster.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Additional Policy Information
Notification of Privacy Statement Changes
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
Links to Other websites
Our Site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of NATIONMASTER. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.
Contact Information
You can contact us about this privacy statement by writing or email us at the address below:
NATIONMASTER Data Protection Officer
Email: gdpr@nationmaster.com
×
Embed content
Add NationMaster content to your website. Copy code below and paste it into your website.
Adblocker detected! Please consider reading this notice.
We've detected that you are using AdBlock Plus or some other adblocking software which is preventing the page from fully loading.
We don't have any banner, Flash, animation, obnoxious sound, or popup ad. We do not implement these annoying types of ads!
We need money to operate the site, and almost all of it comes from our online advertising.
Please add www.nationmaster.com to your ad blocking whitelist or disable your adblocking software.
×
